Liberian Government Archives II, 1911-1968 LCP2006/003
Liberian Collections
Liberian Government Archives II
1911-1968
Liberian Collections
Holsoe, Svend E.
LCP2006/003
12 cubic feet; 1 document case
The collection consists of correspondence, reports, records, minutes, and other miscellaneous manuscript items. These materials are typically either photocopies of items from the Liberian Archives in Monrovia, Liberia, or are typescript copies/notes created by Dr. Holsoe in the course of his research. The collection also includes material from the research notebooks of Dr. Peter Murdza.
Access Restrictions
Closed for research.
Biographical Note
Over the course of his prolific scholarly career, anthropologist Svend Einar Holsoe has greatly advanced our knowledge and understanding of the history and culture of the peoples of Liberia. During his youth, Holsoe's family lived in Liberia for nine years. His interest in a close study of this country and its peoples began during his senior year in high school. Asked to write an essay on his hometown for his senior English course, Holsoe chose Monrovia, only to discover the dearth of material on the nation and its people. It was at this moment, he says, that he dedicated himself to finding and collecting printed materials on Liberia.
Unparalleled in his dedication to the preservation of documents and artifacts on Liberia, in 1997 Holsoe donated his collection of materials to Indiana University's Archives of Traditional Music, Liberian Collections Project, Mathers Museum, and Art Museum. A product of his years of research and relentless materials collection, The Svend E. Holsoe Collection is one of the largest and most comprehensive deposits of resources on the West African nation. The Collection includes: copies of Liberian Government Archive Documents between 1824-1983; extensive genealogical records, including analyses and family trees developed from these records; political, institutional, social and cultural surveys from the 1980s Liberia Rural Radio Project; field notes and oral history tapes of Vai and Bandi research; Vai script materials, including research notes, examples and articles; and slides and photos spanning decades and covering many geographical areas and activities. Due to looting and the destruction of Liberia's National Archives during the civil war that began in 1989, the Liberian Government Archives, part of the Holsoe Collection, contains the only extant copies of important historical and cultural documents.
During his career, Holsoe published numerous important scholarly contributions on Liberia. As early as 1966, Holsoe's article, "The Condo Confederation in Western Liberia," was published in the Liberian Historical Review. Over the next thirty years, Holsoe wrote twenty-seven articles related to Liberia for numerous publications. Holsoe and D. Elwood Dunn collaborated on the first edition of The Historical Dictionary of Liberia ( 1984 ). He followed up this major project as a co-author of A Land and Life Remembered: Americo-Liberian Folk Architecture ( 1988 ). More recently, he co-edited African American Exploration in West Africa ( 2003 ).
A co-founder of the Liberian Studies Association, Holsoe created and edited the Liberian Studies Journal from 1968 to 1978, as well as a Liberian Studies Monograph Series. In 1999, Indiana University awarded Holsoe the Chancellors' Medallion in honor of his unique contributions to scholarship. In presenting the honor, Chancellor Kenneth Gros Louis said of Holsoe: "We know, thanks to his collecting and preserving, thanks to his selfless donation to a public university which will make his work available to all in what we hope will be perpetuity, that Svend Holsoe has done more than his part to ensure that much of what constitutes the country and the cultures of Liberia will remain, and that we, as stewards of his materials, will harvest richly from his efforts." Indeed, Holsoe's scholarly legacy and invaluable collection will long remain an indispensable source of information and inspiration to future scholars of Liberia.
Scope and Content
The materials range chronologically from 1911-1968, though the bulk of the material focuses on three presidents: Dennis E. Howard, C.D.B. King, and Edwin Barclay. There are also a few materials from William Tubman's presidency, mostly as correspondence dealing with international boundaries after World War II. The collection consists of correspondence, reports, records, minutes, and other miscellaneous manuscript items. These materials are typically either photocopies of items from the Liberian Archives in Monrovia, Liberia, or are typescript copies/notes created by Dr. Holsoe in the course of his research (there are also a few hand-written notes)
The collection is divided into three main sections to reflect the three branches of Liberian government: Executive, Legislative, and Judicial. The Executive Branch is further broken down by executive department, with the Presidential materials under the heading "Executive Mansion;" the Legislative by House and Senate; and the Judicial by geographic area and then by court. The organization is intended to reflect the inventory of the Liberian Government Archives as established by Dr. Holsoe and Tom W. Schick (see bibliography). One change in arrangement made to this second part of the collection keeps local materials together. Thus, after departmental correspondence is filed correspondence from local executives by county or province rather than by government agency.
Researchers using the Holsoe Collection Liberian Government Archives will find many items of interest: there is a wealth of correspondence, both intra- and extra-governmental, and the cabinet minutes and Legislative materials provide great insight into the workings of government. Of particular note are the files from President King's term covering the international forced labor scandals in Spanish Guinea, and the encrypted telegrams used during the World Wars. The administration of the interior provinces changed dramatically during this 33-year period until the British system of indirect rule was imported in President Barclay's term. Correspondence on border wars, the Liberian Frontier Force, and the subsequent divisions of the hinterland into tribes and clans can be found.
Acquisition Information
Obtained as part of the collection donated by Dr. Svend Holsoe.
Copyright Transferred
Copyright interests for this collection have been transferred to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, contact the Indiana University Liberian Collections
General
[HT] = Holsoe Typescript
[PC] = Photocopy of Original (or of microfilm)
[MS] = Manuscript Notes
Bibliography - Print Sources
Dunn, D. Elwood, et al. Historical Dictionary of Liberia, Second Edition. London:Scarecrow Press,.
Holsoe, Svend. Liberian Government Archival Documents(Unpublished Manuscript, 1995)
Liebenow, J. Gus. Liberia: The Evolution of Privelege. Ithaca, N.Y.: Cornell University Press, 1969.
Liebenow, J. Gus. Liberia: The Quest for Democracy. Bloomington, Ind.: Indiana University Press, 1987.
Schick, Tom W. "A Catalog of the National Archives of the Liberian Government." History in Africa 3 1976: 193-202
Bibliography - Electronic Sources
http://www.onliberia.org/Liberia.htm
Africa -- Colonization -- History; Liberia -- Foreign Relations -- France; Liberia -- Foreign Relations -- Great Britain; Liberia -- Foreign Relations -- United States; Liberia -- History -- 19th Century; Liberia -- History -- 20th Century; Liberia -- Politics and Government -- 19th Century; Liberia -- Politics and Government -- 20th Century; Liberia -- Social Conditions; African Americans -- Liberia -- History -- 19th Century; American Colonization Society; Indigenous Peoples -- Liberia; Holsoe, Svend E.
- Executive, 1911-1968 (Box 1)
  - Executive Mansion (Box 1)
    - General Correspondence (Box 1)
      - Unidentified/fragmentary, n.d., 10 Items (Box 1)
        General
        [PC]
      - 1912-1915, 55 Items (Box 1)
        [PC & HT]
      - 1916-1967, 45 Items (Box 1)
      - Administrative Specialist, 1937-1939; 39 Items (Box 1)
      - Firestone Plantation, 1925; 12 Items (Box 1)
      - Firestone Plantation, 1926-1937; 23 Items (Box 1)
      - Firestone Plantation, 1938-1940; 16 Items (Box 1)
      - Borkai Masalay Case, 1946-1947; 30 Items (Box 1)
      - Cabinet Meetings, 1911-1919; 14 Items (Box 1)
    - Domestic Correspondence - Departmental (Box 1)
      - General, 1911-1916; 12 Items (Box 1)
      - General, 1917-1930; 13 Items (Box 1)
      - General, 1931-1943; 18 Items (Box 1)
      - Boundary Commission, 1912-1919; 17 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Agriculture, 1924-1926; 3 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Agriculture, 1940-1942; 6 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Health & Sanitation, 1937-1939; 6 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Labor re: Maryland County, 1931; 8 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Public Works, 1931-1937; 9 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs re: Central Province, 1938-1941; 23 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs re: Grand Bassa County, 1938-1939; 24 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs re: Grand Bassa County, 1940-1941; 6 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs re: Grand Cape Mount, 1939-1941; 14 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs re: Western Province, 1938-1939; 28 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs re: Western Province, 1940; 12 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs Report of Bopolu-Suehn District Tour, August 1940; 86 pp. (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs, 1938; 11 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs, 1939; 28 Items (Box 1)
      - Bureau of Tribal Affairs, 1940-1942; 27 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Chiefs, 1915-1919; 13 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Chiefs, 1931-1943; 24 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province District Commissioner, 1915-1916; 2 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Gbanga District Commissioner, 1931-1943; 9 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Kakata District Commissioner, 1931-1943; 13 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Naama District Commissioner, 1923-1930; 3 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Saniquelle District Commissioner, 1923-1930; 4 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Saniquelle District Commissioner, 1931-1943; 15 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Tapita District Commissioner, 1931-1943; 39 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province Zinta District Commissioner, 1923-1930; 2 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province, 1911-1919; 15 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province, 1925; 19 Items (Box 1)
      - Central Province, 1931/1940; 25 Items (Box 1)
      - Chief Mambu Case, 1914-1915; 8 Items (Box 1)
      - Chiefs, 1916-1919; 17 Items (Box 1)
      - Civil Service Commission, 1937-1939; 4 Items (Box 1)
      - Commissioner General re: Grand Cape Mount, 1916-1919; 5 Items (Box 1)
      - Commissioner General, 1915-1919; 13 Items (Box 1)
      - Commissioner-at-Large, 1915-1917; 9 Items (Box 1)
      - Eastern Province, 1935-1937; 16 Items (Box 1)
      - Eastern Province Chiefs, 1933-1935; 7 Items (Box 1)
      - Eastern Province Gbarzon District Commissioner, 1926-1931; 3 Items (Box 1)
      - Eastern Province Juarzon District Commissioner, 1935; 18 Items (Box 1)
      - Eastern Province Tchien District Commissioner, 1935-1942; 37 Items (Box 1)
      - Eastern Province Webo District Commissioner, 1927-1935; 13 Items (Box 1)
      - Grand Bassa, 1911-1919; 23 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1920-1923; 23 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1924; 14 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1926-1929; 9 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1930-1932; 22 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1933-June 1934; 33 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1936-1937; 45 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1938-1941; 29 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, 1942-1943; 19 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, August-December 1925; 15 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, January-May 1925; 18 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, July-August 1934; 23 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, June-July 1925; 29 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, September-December 1934; 29 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, City of Buchanan, 1915-1941; 9 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa, Clan Chiefs, 1931-1943; 9 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa County Superintendent, 1913-1929; 28 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa County Superintendent, 1930-1935; 19 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa County Superintendent, 1936-1943; 29 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa County Commissioner H.Q. Taylor, 1942-1943; 13 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Gbezon District Commissioner, 1925-1926; 2 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Owens Grove and Little Bassa District, 1931-1943; 18 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Paramount Chiefs, 1925-1942; 8 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Special Representative T. Elwood Davis, July-August 1934; 29 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Timbo & River Cess Districts, 1914-1930; 23 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Timbo & River Cess Districts, 1931-1939; 29 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Timbo & River Cess Districts, 1940-1943; 9 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Bassa Timbo & River Cess Paramount Chiefs, 1927-1943; 14 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1911-1912; 21 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1913-1917; 25 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1918-1919; 30 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1920-1926; 24 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1927-1929; 31 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1930-1931; 25 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1932; 22 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1933-1934; 10 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1935; 27 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, 1937-1943; 27 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, August-December 1936; 19 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, January-June 1936; 13 Items (Box 2)
      - Grand Cape Mount, July 1936; 10 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount Clan Chiefs, 1916-1919; 23 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount Clan Chiefs, 1930-1943; 23 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1912; 17 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1913; 21 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1914-1915; 10 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1916-1918; 35 Items (Box 3)
        [PC &HT]
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1919-1923; items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1924-1926; 32 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1927-1928; 35 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1929-1934; 32 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1935; 23 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1937-1940; 30 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, 1941-1943; 49 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, January-August, 1936; 22 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, October-December, 1936; 32 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Superintendent, September, 1936; 11 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County District and Town Commissioners, 1913-1929; 10 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County District and Town Commissioners, 1930-1934; 29 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County District and Town Commissioners, 1936-1943; 25 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County District and Town Commissioners, January-September, 1935; 17 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County District and Town Commissioners, October-December, 1935; 28 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Paramount Chiefs, 1916-1919; 14 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Paramount Chiefs, 1920-1929; 4 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Paramount Chiefs, 1930-1934; 17 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Paramount Chiefs, 1935-1943; 23 Items (Box 3)
      - Grand Cape Mount County Robertsport Municipality, 1912-1936; 13 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland, 1914-1925; 22 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland, 1926-1930; 18 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland, June 1930-September 1931; 39 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland, September 1931-April 1934; 29 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland, 1935-1945; 42 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland Clan Chiefs, 1914-1940; 8 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland Count Legislators, 1931-1940; 9 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland Superintendent, 1914-1916; 24 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland Superintendent, 1917-1918; 22 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland Superintendent, 1924-1943; 46 Items (Box 3)
      - Maryland County True Whig Party, 1931-1943; 17 Items (Box 4)
      - Maryland District & Town Commissioners, 1912-1916; 3 Items (Box 4)
      - Maryland District & Town Commissioners, 1924-1941; 28 Items (Box 4)
      - Maryland Paramount Chiefs, 1931-1942; 9 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, 1911-1920; 49 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, 1921-1930; 18 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, 1931-1935; 31 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, 1936; 45 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, 1937-1938; 54 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, 1939-1943; 24 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado Chiefs, 1931-1945; 17 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado County Superintendent & Commissioners, 1915-1943; 28 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado County True Whig Party, 1937-1942; 11 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, Governor of Krutown, 1911-1920; 30 Items (Box 4)
      - Montserrado, Liberian College, 1935-1938; 7 Items (Box 4)
      - Native African Commissioner, 1917-1918; 7 Items (Box 4)
      - Native African Commissioner, 1921-1931; 6 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1912-1916; 18 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, January-June 1916; 26 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, August 1916-August 1917; 19 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, September 1917-February 1918; 19 Items (Box 4)
        [PC, HT & MS]
      - Secretary of Interior, March-December 1918; 9 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1919; 9 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1920-1925; 40 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, January-August 1926; 25 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, September 1926-1927; 7 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1928; 20 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1930; 37 pp. (Box 4)
        Large Print
      - Secretary of Interior, May-June 1930; 28 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, July-October 1930; 4 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, December 1930-August 1931; 24 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, September 1931-February 1932; 34 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1933; 30 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1936-1937; 30 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, 1938-1939; 21 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, January-June 1940; 26 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, July-October 1940; 8 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, November-December 1940; 10 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, April-June 1941; 16 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, July-September 1941; 18 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, October-December 1941; 13 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, January-March 1942; 14 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, July 1942; 6 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior, August 1942-December 1943; 3 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Central Province, 1912-1919; 19 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Central Province, 1925-1930; 5 Items (Box 4)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Central Province, 1931; 16 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Central Province, 1932-1939; 21 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Central Province, 1940; 16 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Central Province, 1941-1943; 14 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: District Commissioner Fahnbulleh, 1934; 2 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Grand Cape Mount, 1916-1935; 27 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Grand Cape Mount, 1936-1941; 12 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Grand Bassa, 1912-1943; 38 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Montserrado, 1932-1936; 10 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Montserrado, 1937-1940; 20 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Montserrado, 1941-1943; 21 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Sinoe, 1931-1942; 17 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Western Province, 1930-1933; 18 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Western Province, 1934-1937; 20 Items (Box 5)
      - Secretary of Interior re: Western Province Bopolu Suehn District, 1931-1942; 10 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe, 1911-1920; 23 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe, 1921-1930; 15 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe, 1931-1932; 37 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe, 1933-1938; 30 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe, 1939; 36 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe, 1940-1943; 27 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe, 1959; 2 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe Clan Chiefs, 1917; 1931-1943; 17 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe County Liberian Frontier Force Sasstown Report, 16 January 1940; 197 pp. (Box 5)
      - Sinoe County Special Investigation, 1938; 79 pp. (Box 5)
      - Sinoe County Superintendent, 1911-1925; 79 pp. (Box 5)
      - Sinoe County Superintendent, 1932; 8 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe County Superintendent, 1934-1938; 13 Items (Box 5)
        [PC & HT ]
      - Sinoe County Superintendent, 1934-1948; 22 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe County True Whig Party, 1914-1938; 14 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe District Commissioners, 1917; 3 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe District Commissioners, 1931-1943; 22 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe Paramount Chiefs, 1925-1943; 13 Items (Box 5)
      - Sinoe Special Commission Report on Kru Uprising, 1915-1916; 54 pp. (Box 5)
      - Sinoe Special Commissioner, 1931-1932; 9 Items (Box 5)
      - Western Province, 1911-1920; 15 Items (Box 5)
      - Western Province, 1921-1930; 9 Items (Box 5)
      - Western Province, 1931-1935; 33 Items (Box 5)
      - Western Province Voiinjama-Kolahun District, 1936-1942; 44 Items (Box 5)
      - Western Province Bopolu Suehn District Commissioner, 1936-1943; 27 Items (Box 5)
      - Western Province Bopolu Suehn District, 1931-1939; 9 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Bopolu Suehn District, 1940-1941; 15 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Bopolu Suehn District Chiefs, 1936-1943; 22 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Chiefs, 1931-1939; 25 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Chiefs, 1940-1941; 34 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Kongba District, 1914-1916; 8 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Tengea District Commissioner, 1912-1913; 7 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, 1931-1935; 30 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, January-July 1936; 17 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, August 1936-1937; 23 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, January-April 1940; 19 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, May-June 1940; 15 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, July-December 1940; 33 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, January-June 1941; 34 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, July-November 1941; 20 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, December 1941; 6 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Commissioner, 1943; 5 Items (Box 6)
      - Western Province Voinjama-Kolahun District Radiograms, January-June 1941; 96 Items (Box 6)